Imagine that jeep that's coming
to get me better crash on the
corner
in Bolivia
worrying because I'm not going to kill myself I don't
know I would go to work
then
life is that life you have to
make it with what you have
really you
're worrying so much about yourself
sometimes there are people who
die in life and fall into selfishness [
Music]
[Music]
The easy thing is to talk and give it to each other
it's hard but
[Music]
Okay now let's get to it [
Music]
because I've known you for a long time
and because I know how brave you are because I
believe that between people like
us there should be no lies
your situation is delicate
You have to take care of yourself a lot
and I have a
cerebral
disease an annoying thing because you have to
take care of yourself a lot
make no effort whatsoever
[Music]
but you have to ask for a 30 day leave
Here I have a letter for you to give you
permission
during those 30 days
absolutely nothing is done
and come see me later to begin the
treatment
and it's a portal [
Music]
you can  grow old and die of a
cold
[Music] I
can't assure you anything, I can
guarantee you
[Music]
a little water
[Music
] [Music
] [Music] [
Applause
]
[Music] [Music] [
Applause] [Music] [Music] [
Applause]
[Music]
[Applause] [
Music]
Music] [Music]
I dreamed about your father again I
saw him
dressed in white he
told me something that No matter how hard
I try I can't
remember it
[Music]
those dreams are good
whenever I dream about him I feel
happy
or I saw him on his white horse
just like
when I met him out in the country
your father was a handsome royal he
had all the girls in
town crazy
[Music]
let's get back to reality
this morning a pea is coming
but since you don't want to eat it without
rice but no I cooked them
the rice they don't give it until Monday
So you're going to have to go eat at the
pizzeria
this pile You never remember your
father I do
n't know it
seems to me So you don't remember him I
always remember them
with a feeling like that
of life Yes it seems to me that he's by my side I
can't get used to the idea that he wo
n't die and turn into earth and
everything will be over it seems to me that here
everything can't end
The lord there must be something else I don't know what it
is because I'm strong enough to know
that
but he has to do something else
I think that if people thought a little
more about death
There are those who believe that here one can come
kill steal and do whatever one wants
and then everything will be over but nothing of that
maybe I don't know why of course who knows
But
according to what some people say out there there is
another life something else it will be different
Of course because we will no longer have a body we will not
have flesh but
maybe we will be like this like
ether Yes mom the sky It
seems a lie that at this point you
are still talking about those things
[Music] I
neither believe nor stop believing that is what  what is
said
maybe you know that I am a
revolutionary now what I can't get my
head around
Is that one dies
becomes earth and that's all over
I think that I think there is something more
[Music]
maybe we will
meet up there
someday and then we will see if this life
was right
Ah Look I had forgotten to tell you that
your brother called you he
has a problem with some papers
that he says he wants you to solve alone
Isabel Yes I want to talk to
a boy But I think that you can
call him
if it can be solved he will solve it for you if not you
tell him that he can't what I don't
think is right is that you don't call him after all he
is your brother Look mom I can't
be solving problems for
people who leave the country even though he is
my brother
that boy has gone crazy it's
not all
Berta's fault
that girl so much
[Music]
and the accumulator
this car is falling to pieces
But anyway why would he
enjoy it anyway I have my hands it
's an
outing
Juanita the sister-in-law
at the house of  the people they went to the
little lakes says that he is living at
Alicia's house, Luisa's sister
waiting and nothing or rather 4 years he
is working with a
dairy
a photograph or where they are having breakfast
rather the little package
and the plantains too what
seems to me that they are not going to put what I
tell you
sacrifice because staying quiet
to see if we find an issue of the house
so that he gives me a hand in the matter
of the papers
the malangas are Caballero in the land
of the malanga
that does not start Carlos hey caballero look I
told you I told you leave the
machine alone they are going to screw up our
exit and it breaks
[Music]
[Music] [
Applause] [
Music] [Applause] [Music] [
Music]
[Applause]
match
[Music]
feels bad
thank you
How good I had forgotten to thank
the Lord thank you for nothing
It seems that the gentleman is a
very kind person not one of a special education
or maybe he is nothing more than vulgar and
like a  conqueror who walks through these
parks came to see what falls
the other
[Music]
he likes flowers I've
never thought about that I've never
thought about that
admit beauty no
[Music]
you what's your name
you change the conversation
my name is Lucia
but I would have liked to be called Luisa
[Music]
And you
what do you do
design
and you
but death
but I want to live cultivate melodrama you
're making fun of me it
's a joke don't pay attention to me I'm very
playful
[Music] I'm
going to tell you something but I can't
tell it to anyone I swear I won't say it
[Music]
I like flowers Silvestre
[Music] [
Laughter] [Music] [Music] [Music] [Music] [
Music] [Music] [
Applause] [
Music] [Applause] [Music]
[Applause]
[Music]
[Music] you
arrived a long time ago
coffee you get like that potatoes also arrived
of that pink one that you like
there are a lot of people
[Applause]
[Music]
bad here so it doesn't go away
Because I do know well what has happened
in this country
here there was a time
when we saw there at the end
figure of you that we got up at sunrise
my brother and I went to pick coffee or
to Pilar tobacco we spent
the day working working and when
the time came to eat flour composing it is
many times without sweet potato which was the most
no more the big one
still seems to me also the whole face
of my mother Poor thing may she rest in peace
and my father
despite the fact that he was a strong man but
sometimes he wanted to cry
Looking at his children without shoes and
working like animals
That was great of
course there was also a time well You know
why when
a war
The thing is that sugar went up and
then came that famous time of the
short cow money ran
I remember that your grandfather even bought
a goat because your uncle Antonio who
was little Then
the doctor ordered that they give you
goat's milk because he was very sick of the
stomach
but later my son  I came there during the
moratoriums
you know how people were on the
streets
hungry that for a gatica of flour
they would kill anyone no
one remembers that and that is what they
must have remembered when they threw
people out on the street because they didn't pay the
rent the furniture to be waxed and if at
three it wasn't picked up for the two of you
you were left without a bed to lie down
and people forgot about that I don't know
now they have everything they have jobs they have
school for
the kids they have food Because here no one dies of hunger and still stays I would like to see them in that time well that's life I think that life should be dissatisfaction Rebellion something else I don't know sometimes you have to leave everything and become a guerrilla for
example
That is living there are
many other things of course
in my case my case is more like trying to
destroy everything that is stupid when you
can
Starting with many things about myself
and also there is love in all this there
is also a little bit of Love love for a cause
for something
[Music]
of course you also have to love
someone
So if not  he achieves it he
is a complete human being
So I have no reason to worry
I am full of life
And then why do you talk to me so much about
death it
occurred to you now
[Music]
I think that maybe
maybe you are selfish
maybe no more enough
you could help me I
dry I
lack you of love
You say that love is life
[Music]
[Applause] [
Music] thank you
sorry I
had forgotten to thank
the Lord
[Music]
I feel good
[Music] the
same thing happens to me
[Music]
[Applause]
the work I went through to get
this money
no And the lucky thing is that I have
a friend named Maria Antonia who has been
waiting for her release for two years it makes
me feel sorry
you know what she does it's two years
but oh well
everyone Well
as soon as I told her that you
were there for you to celebrate your birthday today
Then I told her look Maria Antonia
what I need is for you to
get some plantains because you know
that some fried plantains on a table  It's
true that many people dress, they are a thing
that brings joy to life, so don't
worry, don't worry, then she
got me, she said, I'll be
able to get there again, to this
place where I have the farm. I mean, not
my aunt who has a small farm over there.
What's the name of the place?
So she got me the gas and everything
from yesterday, she left the bananas at my
house, that's why you think at least a few
bananas. So I am
grateful that you
came.
That was the main thing,
the rest I manage well with what they
give.
Look at six in the afternoon, I go
to the winery every day, I buy bread, I make
my Judith and they turn out pretty good here. There's
never a lack of dessert.
Well, Josefina, but to make what you
call a pudding,
what's up? I
looked at my farmhouse, some puddings that I put
fruit in, butter, milk, I was
talking about food,
what's going on, I'm not alone, you know.
That's the topic of the day, and if not, I'll ask
Josefina, let's see, Josefina,
tell me, you who spend your life
at the wineries, people don't spend all
day talking about food, in the morning,
in the afternoon,
it's that people  There's no other topic of
conversation
I try to think of something else and I'm doing
better More important things
They'll forgive me
but son How are you going to leave like that Sit down They have
n't had coffee yet Praised
Esteban It seems like a lie that you
do to them Josefina on her
birthday please
[Music]
The problem seems to me that it's better not to
continue You don't believe Well and whatever you
want It seems to me that we shouldn't
be so sensitive
Well
Shut up Berta
calm down
I'm not willing to sacrifice
[Music]
Come on Let's get out of here
[Music] They make
me feel sorry
[Music]
The thing is that I don't like that people
say
that
arm but
a good doctor is not a good teacher
[Music]
[Applause]
[Music] I
don't know the
situation is very difficult I
would have to put myself in your place I
would fight in your place
[Music]
Precisely in
difficult situations where one has to grow
as a revolutionary man
I am very attached to life it would
never occur to me
you understand
my life has two  faces
or two facets but a part of the
revolution
On the other hand
women
what do I know
[Music] I do
n't know if I'm helping you
if I'm putting in my part but
I you will work
with certain conditions
and
if I couldn't then I would retire you
can you can take a
subsidy
[Music]
perfectly
I know that a little harsh what I'm
telling you but
if you needed
for example apartment
anything guys no problem
and the other facet
the revolution I already told you I would work
as much as possible
[Music]
besides boy Look if if someone has done
this for me
I know that you've been in this since you
were almost a child of
course it was that one never finishes no but I do
n't believe anything you've told me Pepe
Forgive me I'm Franco
your solution is of no use to me I
would prefer to die right now anyway it doesn't matter
besides
I'm not so sure that I've done as much
as you say
And I think that should never be a
conclusion I
'm satisfied something has failed there has to be
another way there must be
another solution
Don't worry that would be betraying
myself
yes on vacation
[Music]
I also have the right
tell me  something Alicia How are you doing
You don't say you're on vacation Well
look Enjoy it because if I tell you I don't
have time for
it You followed the factory, you
understand what I mean There are boys But yes
Esteban too, something with all the
honors, florecita band and everything Yes, they
told me that there is good work there you're
not right
Imagine when I got there it didn't
look like a factory it was something like a
trail of rusty pieces that I was
working on When they sent me it was
all that dead patriotic thing that
for me they work with the chairs besides
the proof is that now it's on a good
farm Well, the guy would show up at
nine in the morning, quietly,
to set an example, imagine and he arrived
at that time, at 9 in the morning, he went out
to the street to solve problems,
matters, he didn't return all day,
then he had taken to speaking in the
meetings, it
was like demagoguery raised to the cube In
reality, I wasn't going to be able to do anything
there
with the people, we discussed, analyzed one
of things and in less than 15 days
I calculate, things started to work
perfectly.  They blocked some
things like for example the dining room, we did
n't have a dining room, we made a
beautiful dining room. By the way, it turned out
fantastic, we did it as
volunteer work on Sundays. Then we had
a problem with supplies. We
went to the beginning, we solved it in two
or three days, we had all the
supplies in the factory,
so what we had left was the problem of
awareness, which there was no awareness. Well,
look, we talked little and worked with a
Torah and we basically dealt with the
human problem,
discuss with the people, talk to them,
be one more there because that's really how it is. I
feel very, wow. I don't know, I think
things work very well, so it
works well, there's no problem with the
others and now I don't have any other goal than the
national ambulation, I
iron myself out but I'm going to win it
and after that,
nobody can take the vacation away from me. After that, I'll invite you
and speaking of vacation, tell me what you're
doing. In reality, I'm not on vacation.
[Music]
because we're not going to a quiet place and
talking.
[Music] [
Applause]
[Music]
I have to do something.
find a way out,
I can't  to receive a benefit
I can't stay in the house to wait
I would tell you to come with me to the
factory
So there are many beautiful things to do you
have to work hard
maybe you can help me this
[Music] it
's horrible not knowing anything
I can't accept this life
[Music]
in discretion I
didn't know I could die
but death wanted a meaning it
wasn't useless
[Music]
[Music] [Music] [Music] [Music] [Music] [Music]
okay
[Music] they
told me
tonight Pauta linda Elsa it
's a delicate job
you're going to a concert
a very young man will sit next to you
[Music] he will
deliver a package
take it as if it were a gift
[Applause]
[Music]
then he will leave
then you
but we commit an indiscipline
we stay
the music It was so beautiful
[Music]
and that was such a tense time
only news of deaths were received
[Music]
torture
betrayal
[Music]
that was
like a sedative for us
it was like nothing was happening
[Applause]
[Music]
What's wrong with you being nothing It's
just that I'm 42 years old
[Music]
according to statistics this State for
women
I'm not an exceptional case I
say nonsense
[Applause]
[Music]
I'm here with you
Who says they're alone besides you have
your job your friends
you know that in this country you're not alone you're
right
but I'm alone
[Music]
what worries me is that sometimes at
work
I'm aggressive
[Music]
Unfair
[Applause]
And that's not right
[Music]
You have to be strong
there are things that one cannot allow do
n't worry
[Music] I'm
not going to become an anecdote
we have a lot to do
[Music]
bad weather
for now I have to look for something
some course of something
[Music]
Come so you can see the new project I
'm working on I
think it's good
[Music]
Tell me something about you I
know
You have more to tell than I do
[Music]
And the truth is Esteban
Very old hair
[Music]
I mean
you are a very pretty woman
always have been
always will be [
Music]
[Applause]
[Music]
I would have liked to study engineering
but with the insurrection it was impossible for me
and then when the revolution triumphed well it
seemed very selfish at first to
dedicate myself to studying nothing more with the
amount of things that there were to do
I spent the first three years
working all the time morning afternoon and
night almost without being able to sleep
so after that I started working at the
Ministry doing the same thing I am now
In short it is a job that I never
liked but I saw it as very useful at the
beginning
But and now I feel
very satisfied with the work this is
too mechanized I have
thought about going to work in another place I do
n't know some physical job
meet another type of people with other
problems more dynamic problems
more concrete problems
And then come back and enroll
engineering again
and I've brought it up at work on
several occasions but they always tell me
the same thing
some of them have their reasons of
course I think it's been weak I've also had to
live through a different stage
Maybe for my Generation it's easier
I don't want it
I don't want to get old and have to
regret what I didn't do I don't
want to waste time of
course I went to one school then to another in another
first painting then chemistry
to finally end up in design which
has nothing to do with chemistry
but oh well
now I feel good I think I've finally
found what I want I really like
what I'm doing
And what do you think
in two months you'll be in veterinary medicine
Don't make that face it was a joke I do
n't feel well
[Music]
what's wrong with you
Maybe you think it's ridiculous
but I think I'm falling in love with you
here I'm going to do it
[Music]
[Applause]
next month we're leaving for
productive work
I'll have a good time it
's not exactly that I have fun in the field
or I go just for fun
I think it's a necessity I think it
's something more than a  Consignment I don't know it's
so nice to be all together like this
in a group
besides I get free from Havana from my
parents in reality there is no
possibility of
communication between them and
in their world I live in my own I do
n't know
you know they have made a scheme of
life then the Revolution comes and
everything changed it is
said to be very revolutionary but In
short the only thing they have done is
adapt their petty bourgeois mentality to
therevolution I
talk to them and talk to them It
's as if I were talking to them in another language
besides at home I feel very alone it's
not that I don't like loneliness
but sometimes sometimes you want to talk
to someone I don't know how to say things that you
understand
now they say I'm a libertine what do you
think of that I
think I think a bit like
[Music] in
the summers we would go to Aunt Emilia's house
[Music] she
was a very happy woman
had a constant struggle with the
almanac
so it seems that to feel
younger she would invite a group of boys to
her house
we would meet there to talk
[Music]
one summer everything changed
and those young people had stopped  being
children completely the meetings were of
Conspiracy c  against The dictatorship
everything outside of Aunt Emilia Of course She
never found out About anything
besides there was a new person in the
group
a girl daughter
of course she was already conspiring too
and you I
joined
I joined to conspire too
[Music]
sometimes I think that for the ideal
also to please her a little
Because
because you consider me and respect me I
told her father he found out everything they
took him away I
felt very bad but the first time I had been
in love
then I went to Havana and the fight continues
[Music]
of course you could say that you were very young
in reality there is no true
personal fulfillment that is not at the same
time social
And that age is very emotional
older was more decisive for you
what you felt than what you thought
affection was what drove you
very brilliant all that
but thanks to that emotionality of people
like me that you are sitting here
theorizing
about all the people of your generation can be
studying can be enjoying
life
without having to worry about the future
well agreed but I'm going to tell you one
thing
we  we would have done the same thing
maybe
[Music]
[Applause]
[Applause] [
Music]
Music] [
Applause] [
Music]
[Applause] [
[Applause]
[Music]
I know that the eyes always
skirts bending every day
but after everything what happens to me
has happened to thousands of women
[Music]
Doña Rosita the single woman third act
Esteban what's wrong with you
[Music] I
'm not worried
why don't you tell me
sometimes you let it all out then you
feel better
[Applause]
[Music]
I've been Here
looking over old photos and remembering since
time goes by fast this seems like it
was yesterday and it's been a few  how many years ago this
happened to
you is something wrong with you I don't know why I have the
impression that you're hiding something from me
if something happens to you tell me because the most
unpleasant thing for someone is to find out about
their children from strangers
[Music] Do
n't worry mom there's no
problem
that's how it is it's fine
look in this photo you look very good
if it weren't for the fact that Eduardo is that idiot he
decided to make a face it's a
shame because the photograph was
good right
Here's one from when you went to
school
you still remember from the little dog
[Music]
and this friend was looking at you
This is the beach from when you used to
spend time at Emilia's house do you
remember
Here it's very good
[Music]
[Applause] [
Music] [Applause] [Music] [Applause] [
Music]
[Applause]
[Music]
when I feel sentimental logically
like everyone else what you need is a
cigarette a
sip half light the record player and that's it eh
And that time  Paquito was opening a
club there in the car and he dressed up as
China But he had a wonderful outfit I do
n't know where he got it but it was wonderful from
Chile and they dressed me up
I put on a Manuela
costume a lot of good outfits and I had
black hair around here they filled it with little
colored combs well She was
a real cutie and I said to my brother
Oh no my brother is a
first class dancer And I said nothing
[Music]
Aunt I want to ask you something
What are you most afraid of in
life old
age my life what do you think
The most terrible thing there is everything else
can be overcome
but old age can't
and especially not that one goes by
time and time and
when you come to see
the years go by and one Ultimately hasn't
done anything fruitful nor resolved
anything and everything continues the same
[Music]
boy Because I don't know when it went a
little bit
regulated and then one starts looking in the
mirror and what if a gray hair here and
a wrinkle on the other side well no it's not
ugly  that's
ugly now anyway you have to
receive it you have to
receive it later sooner
you're not afraid of it at the same time of
course they give it to you at
your age if you're in the prime of your life
when I had it I didn't think about
that but now yes
now you know how it is you have to
be with the creams and with
the things that's the reality
[Music]
[Applause]
[Laughter]
[Music]
you are the greatest
without you there isn't so much no oath you are
the
ugly
holy color no oath you are the faith it wo
n't be long
[Applause]
[Music]
[Applause] [
Music]
[Applause] [Music] [Applause]
[Music] would
you marry me
maybe if you had told me that a
long time ago I would have
smiled at first
This would have made me cry
and with all these contradictions
and look at your arms they know more than anything
out of gratitude I
was going to do it I was
not going to do it
with you
but no I
believe that marriage is a
Conception
surrender
is difficult because I would also like in
any case many things would have to be clarified
I am not one of those women who try to
fulfill themselves through the marriage of their
children it
would have to be something different
a more humane birth
for you it is very easy Of course
you can live with the good In any case ways
of training
I do not want to get frustrated neither as a woman nor
my profession
becomes a monotony
I want to fulfill myself
I do not think that it is enough that
women join the workforce just like
men it
is enough there are
not many things to change to do that need to be
clarified
I am impatient
besides I do not think that you are ready
for that I
think you can understand
not to feel it
maybe it would be
good I do
not
think that I would not get married I
think that you are right in many of the
things that you say
in what I do not believe in your solution It
seems to me that yes that marriage that
you talk about It frustrates you
but
if you give up on them You are also giving up on
a partner you are giving up
your children
that frustrates you too
because you have to search is to achieve that
relationship in your own way
[Music] to
achieve a marriage like the one that you
want
[Music]
And that Ultimately it  that will
complete the realization
[Music]
[Music] it's
not worth it I'm
going to the countryside
and I'll come back to the university
[Music]
all useless
[Music] it
's horrible
you're right
maybe we could find a solution together
maybe we could go to the countryside
[Music] we
could get married if you want
[Music]
[Applause] [
Music]
that I never believed that
losing an arm would
change your life so much And why is that
Because it sings
inside a different one
[Music] it
already has
and if it's not going to take the power
it shoots itself it becomes [Music
]
[Music] [
Music]
[Applause] [Music
] [Music
] [Music] [Music] [Music]
[Music]
better Thank you
but since now we work and study
the practice and the and the thing is Also I
'm from the countryside
to measure the skin
[Music]
the little hand
[Music] I
say the bandit soldiers or what
came from there I
lost my vocation I was going to be a pilot but
since you can't fly a plane with a
mochito and I lost let's see what else good
law
[Music]
because you know what a woman is who
wants a man with two arms two two
arms a man and I didn't know was
no good
And that's because
I never knew that by losing an arm
life changes so much
[Music]
and you speak differently
[Music] he
shoots himself it becomes shit
to study
[Music]
I want whoever wants in all the months
what Download everyone well sorry
[Music] I'll
go with you
[Music]
what's going on
I was thinking that
[Music] you
told me without meaning to that I was a piece of shit
that I really needed someone to
tell me tremendously
[Music]
Also I need to explain to you What things you've
donealso
not on the contrary
I'm sick
and it's serious it's
serious the
worst thing is that I find a solution
[Music] I
don't know
[Music]
What has made you think about the other one who is
death
especially when there aren't so many
things left to do
when you're not satisfied with
what you've done
[Music]
it's difficult but
sometimes I think it's too late
On the other hand I don't want to sit and
wait
in reality I don't know what to do
come here
[Music]
You think I don't have a complex
Well yes I do I ca
n't do what you can do you
what do you have the arms
but you have found a solution
[Music] I have
found it yourself Despite
everything
you have fought
instead
I thought of doing so many things
so many things that I haven't done
Look
Imagine that the jeep is going to come and get me it's
here
in Bolivia
but I can't be thinking Now or
worrying about it because if not I won't
go out on the street if not I won't go to work
I'll stay at home sitting down you I
'm not a philosopher No but really There
is an answer for which there are truths and
then you can't be so selfish you
have to think a little about others Go on Do
n't die in life You
understand work I
don't know how to go and do anything
[Music]
but it's that
damn what  It's easy to give advice
and how easy it is to talk
[Music]
and how hard
for it to be
[Music]
well
And I have to be at
the unit at five bye
Well friends And this doesn't stop the
party continues with great joy in
honor of this Heroic comrades who
have known how to earn with their effort the
emulation of the school and the countryside up
comrade a round of applause for them
Come and more music
[Music] [
Music] [
Music] [Applause]
[Music] [
Music]
[Applause] [
Music] [
Applause] [
Applause]
[Music] [Applause]
[Music]
[Applause] [Music
]